{
    "id": "5f581e1c56ff4be9a6bd5e15041182f3",
    "title": "Tenses Worksheet",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The Red Cross ……………………. food and shelter for disaster victims.",
            "description": "Use the simple present to talk about facts. When the subject is a singular noun, the verb takes the marker -s in the simple present tense.",
            "answers": [
                "provide",
                "providing",
                "provides"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Her constant nagging ……………………… him.",
            "description": "To simply say that something happened, we use the simple past. ",
            "answers": [
                "provoke",
                "provoked",
                "provoking"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The island ……………………….. with overgrown greenery.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "covered",
                "was covered",
                "has covered"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The islanders were warned that a storm …………………….. coming.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, the verb in the subordinate clause too will be in the past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The student’s work ……………………… unsatisfactory.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "were judged",
                "was judged",
                "has judged"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Revisions ……………………….. to bring the text up to date.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "were made",
                "was made",
                "have made"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Criminals ……………………….. to return to the scene of crime.",
            "description": "This is the passive version of the simple present tense. The simple present is used to talk about facts. ",
            "answers": [
                "have said",
                "were said",
                "are said"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………….. South America in my youth.",
            "description": "The simple past is used when we say when something happened.",
            "answers": [
                "visited",
                "have visited",
                "has visited"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Many pilgrims ………………………. his same path to the shrine.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to give news. ",
            "answers": [
                "are trod",
                "has trod",
                "have trod"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He ............................ the rest of his life in the wheelchair.",
            "description": "The simple past is the most common tense for talking about finished events. ",
            "answers": [
                "spends",
                "spent",
                "has spent"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ................................ to go.",
            "description": "Would like is common in polite requests. ",
            "answers": [
                "like",
                "will like",
                "would like"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}